A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Associate Director and Vice President, Office Files of William McPeak FA704
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Associate Director and Vice President, Office Files of William McPeak
1949-1965
Rockefeller Archive Center
McPeak, William Wallace
Ford Foundation
FA704
3.8 Cubic Feet
The Office Files of William McPeak provide a partial record of his activities as Associate Director and, later Vice President, at the Ford Foundation between 1950-1964. The files have been in the Foundation Archives since the 1970s. It was not possible to reconstruct the original order of the files because, at some point, the Office Files were reorganized. Evidence of this is the placement of items in folders bearing titles which are different from the notation written on the upper right-hand corner of the item. For example, letters marked "Consultants - Fels, Wm. C." were refiled under "CEEB." For this reason the processor imposed an artificial order and created series.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Separated Materials
Speeches, articles, and reports by staff and consultants relating to Ford Foundation activities were removed from Mr. McPeak's office files and transferred to the appropriate record groups. A cross-reference sheet was inserted for each removed item. Removed reports and articles are listed in Appendix A, and removed speeches are listed in Appendix B.
Biographical / Historical
William McPeak was an Assistant Director of the Study for the Ford Foundation on Policy and Program from 1948-1950. Between 1953 and 1964 he held the following administrative positions at the Ford Foundation:
- 1962-64 Vice President Office of Policy Planning
- 1955-62 Vice President Administration
- 1954 Acting President
- 1953-1955 Associate Director Education, Behavioral Sciences
William McPeak was born August 4, 1908. He received his Bachelor of Science degree in 1933 from George Washington Evening school (Washington, DC). Prior to his career at the Ford Foundation, Mr. McPeak held the following positions:
- 1950-53, Executive Director, Ford Motor Company Fund
- 1948, Executive Assistant, Hoover Commission, Medical Manpower Subcommittee
- 1948, Study Director, American Heart Association
- 1948, Associate, Raymond Rich Associates, Public Relations
- 1946-48, Study Director, Association for the Aid of Crippled Children
- 1941-45, Chief of Development Section, United States War Department, Information and Education Division
- 1940-41, Associate Agricultural Program Analyst, United States Department of Agriculture
- 1929-34, Correspondent, Partner, Washington Press Service
His publications include the articles, "Problems of Field Management in Army Opinion Research" for the Journal of the American Statistical Association, "Pediatricians' Views Concerning Problems of the Handicapped" in the Journal of the American Academy of Pediatrics, and the chapter "Scholarships and Fellowships" in the book, Manual of Corporate Giving, edited by Beardsley Ruml.
Mr. McPeak died on March 31, 1964.
Scope and Contents
The Office of the Associate Director/Vice President Office Files of William McPeak consist of 4.25 linear feet of correspondence and inter-office memoranda. These files give an incomplete documentation of some of the activities of William McPeak in the administration of the Ford Foundation and in the Program areas of education and behavioral science.
The research strength of these files is two-fold: the documentation of Mr. McPeak's formulation of policy, and his role in implementing it at the Ford Foundation in its first decade. Correspondence in Series I, Administration, is especially rich in this respect. There is a very small amount of correspondence from Mr. McPeak's tenure at the Ford Motor Company Fund where he worked in their scholarship program.
There is a limited amount of hard information in Mr. Peak's files; it is suggested that the researcher use these records in conjunction with other Foundation Holdings. Some topics mentioned in the files include: educational television, release time for faculty for educational television programming, the University of Chicago Law School grant, the Foundation's public relations efforts, the college grants program, juvenile delinquency, and the relationship between the Foundation and its intermediaries--including grantees and Funds. Correspondents include: Paul Bixler, Dyke Brown, Fred Cole, H. Rowan Gaither, Earl Newsom, Beardsley Ruml, William C. Fels, Milton Katz, Paul Lazarsfeld, and W. McNeil Lowry. There is no correspondence with the following institutions: American Council on Education, American Library Association, College Entrance Examination Board, Library of Congress, National Social Welfare Assembly, and the Social Science Research Council.
The files do not include Mr. McPeak's records of the Study for the Ford Foundation on Policy and Program (Study Committee) or the records of the 1955 special appropriations for raising faculty salaries, for medical schools, and for private hospitals. Much of this information is available elsewhere in the Archives.
Arrangement
The Office of the Associate Director/Vice President Office Files of William McPeak have been divided into four series:
I. Administration
II. Program Area IV: Education in a Democratic Society
III. Program Area V: Individual Behavior and Human Relations
IV. Program Areas I, II, and III
Within each series the files are arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
- Administration, 1949-1965; 1954-1956; I
  Arrangement
  Series I, Administration, consists of correspondence and inter-office memoranda and is divided into the following five subseries:
  A. Organization and Policy
  B. Program Committee
  C. Congressional Investigation
  D. Correspondence
  E. Speeches and Writings
  Each subseries is arranged alphabetically. Within each folder items are in reverse chronological order.
  - Organization and Policy, 1949-1958; A
    - Annual Report, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Background Information Statement, 1954 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - By-Laws, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Consultants, circa 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Docket, 1953 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Financial - Financial, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Financial - Grant Estimates, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Financial - Internal Revenue Code, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ford Foundation Relationship with Intermediaries, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ford Foundation Releases, 1954 June-August (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Memoranda (misc.), 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Office of Reports, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Personnel, circa 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Principles and Policies of the Ford Foundation, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Program Areas, 1955 August-September (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Program Jurisdiction, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Program Planning Conference, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Public Relations Problems and Policies, 1956 June (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Research Department, 1956 June (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Small Grants Program, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Trustees, circa 1949-1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Program Committee, 1954-1955; B
    - 1954 January 12 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1954 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1954 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1955 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 1955 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Congressional Investigations, 1954-1965; C
    - Elliott Committee - Government Research Grants, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Patman Investigation of Foundations/Treasury Report, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Reece Committee Investigation of Tax-Exempt Foundations - Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Reece Committee Investigation of Tax-Exempt Foundations - Press Summaries, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Reece Committee Investigation of Tax-Exempt Foundations - Summaries of Testimony and Status Reports, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - General Correspondence, 1950-1961; D
    - Aid of Crippled Children, Association for the, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - American Institute for Public Opinion [Gallop], 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bender, W.J., [?] September 10 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Bixler, Paul, 1950-1957 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Brown, Dyke, 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Burdine, J. Alton, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - C, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Carroll, T.H., 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Clark, Grenville, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Cole, Fred, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Cravath, Swaine and Moore, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Corning Glass Works Foundation, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - D, 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Dollard, John, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - E, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Eells, Richard, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - F, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Flexner, Abraham, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Ford Motor Company Fund, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - G, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Gaither, H. Rowan, 1950-1956 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Gladieux, Bernard, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Heald, Henry T., n.d., 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Henry, David D., 1957 August 17 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Jaffe, A.J., 1955 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - K, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Kansas City Association of Trusts and Foundations, 1951-1957 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Larson, Roy, 1955 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Lowry, W. McNeil, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Lyons, Russell, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - M, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - N, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - National Citizens Committee for the Public Schools, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - National Industrial Conference Board, 1955 October 17 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - National Voluntary Health Agencies, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Newsom, Earl - Public Relations Counsel, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Odegard, Peter, 1955 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - P, 1955-1961 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Price, Don, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - R, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Ruml, Beardsley, 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Russell Sage Foundation, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - S, 1950-1957 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1953-1955 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Spencer, Lyle, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Stalnaker, John M., 1953-1955 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Texas, University of, 1955 July (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - U.S. Steel, 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Vassar College, 1955 February 11 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - White, Helen C., 1954 August 6 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Whitney Foundation, 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Young, Robert, 1955 November 14 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Zuckert, Eugene M., 1954 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1951-1960; E
    - "Manual of Corporate Giving" Correspondence, 1951-1956 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - "The Small Frantic Voice of the Patient" Stanford Medical Center Dedicatory Exercises, 1959 May-September (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - "The Small Frantic Voice of the Patient" Reprint of Speech Correspondence, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 89)
- Program Area IV: Education in a Democratic Society, 1952-1959; 1954-1956; II
  Series II consists of correspondence and inter-office memoranda. It is organized alphabetically; within each folder items are arranged in reverse chronological order.
  - Administrative Internship Program, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - American Alumni Council, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - American Association for the Advancement Science, 1956 November 30 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - American Association of Land Grant Colleges, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - American Council on Education - American Council on Education, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - American Council on Education - Committee on Television, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - American Geographical Society, 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - American Historical Association, 1957 January 11 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - American Library Association, 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Association of Graduate Schools, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Atlanta University, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Budget, 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Bundy, McGeorge, 1955 December 30 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Centers for Oriental Studies, 1959 April-June (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Chicago, University of - Chicago, University of, 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Chicago, University of - Center of Chinese Studies, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Chicago, University of - Education, Graduate School of, 1954 March (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Colgate University, 1953 November (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - College Entrance Examination Board, 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - College Grants Program - College Grants Program, 1957-1962 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - College Grants Program - Adjustments in Grants to Institutions with Contributed Services (Catholic), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Correspondence - Council for Financial Aid to Education, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Correspondence - Cravath, Swaine and Moore, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Correspondence - Fund Raising Associations, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Correspondence - General, 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Correspondence - Price Waterhouse, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Correspondence - Regional Accrediting Associations, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Ineligible Institutions, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Inquiries re Investment of Grants, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Problems of Eligibility, undated (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Proration Cases (Private-Public Control), 1956 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Questionnaire - First, 1955 July (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - Questionnaire - Second, Pretest, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - Questionnaire - Second, Catholic, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - Questionnaire - Second, Non-Catholic, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - Questionnaire - Follow-up Report Sheets, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 127)
  - College Investment Trust - Expenses, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - College Investment Trust - Prospectus and Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 129)
  - College Student Loans, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 130)
  - Columbia University, 1955 February-March (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - Commission on Television, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Council on Financial Aid to Education, 1953-1957 (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Council on Library Resources, 1955-1959 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Dartmouth College, 1953-1956 (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Detroit, University of, 1955 April 21 (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Dillard University, 1954 August 3 (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - DuPont de Nemours and Co., 1954-1957 (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - ETV - Ames, Iowa, 1955 September (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - ETV - Boston (MA) WGBH, 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - ETV - Chicago, 1955 June (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - ETV - Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - ETV - Detroit, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - ETV - East Lansing, 1955 July-October (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - ETV - Educational Television and Radio Center, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 145)
  - ETV - Educational Television and Radio Center, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - ETV - Elliot, William Y., 1955 June-September (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - ETV - Fund for Adult Education, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - ETV - Harvard Summer School Meeting, 1956 June-July (Box 5, Folder 149)
  - ETV - Houston, 1956 June-July (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - ETV - Kansas City, 1955 September (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - ETV - Lazarsfeld Study, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - ETV - Minneapolis, 1955 June-July (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - ETV - National Association of Educational Broadcasters, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - ETV - National Citizens Committee on Educational TV, 1955 June-December (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - ETV - New Orleans, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - ETV - Overseas Report, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 157)
  - ETV - Pittsburgh, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 158)
  - ETV - Released Time for Faculty, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 159)
  - ETV - Released Time for Inquiries, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 160)
  - ETV - San Francisco, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 161)
  - ETV - St. Louis, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 162)
  - ETV - Seattle, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 163)
  - ETV - Staff Memos, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 164)
  - ETV - Washington Compact, 1955 October-November (Box 6, Folder 165)
  - ETV - Washington, DC, 1956 January 9 (Box 6, Folder 166)
  - ETV - Winston-Salem and Chapel Hill, 1955 September 7 (Box 6, Folder 167)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1953-1956 (Box 6, Folder 168)
  - Emeriti Census, 1955-1957 (Box 6, Folder 169)
  - Experimental Scholarship Program, 1955 September-October (Box 6, Folder 170)
  - Fells, William C., 1956 August-December (Box 6, Folder 171)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 172)
  - Fund for Adult Education - Correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 6, Folder 173)
  - Fund for Adult Education - Educational Television, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 174)
  - Fund for Adult Education - Policy and Grant Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 175)
  - Fund for Adult Education - Vanderbilt Study, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 176)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Ashmore Project, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 177)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Committee of Fifteen, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 179)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 180)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 181)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Documents Concerning $25M Grant, 1954 February (Box 6, Folder 182)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Fellowships, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Financing College Education of Faculty Children, 1953 November 7 (Box 7, Folder 184)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - History, Scope and Program Statements, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 185)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Keppel Proposal, 1956 February 28 (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education - Queries, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Harvard University - Education, Graduate School of, 1952-1956 (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - Harvard University - General, 1954-1956 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Historical Review of Program Area IV, 1956 September 21 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Illinois, University of, 1954-1957 (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Intercultural Publications - Confluence, 1953 October (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - Intercultural Publications - Relationship with, 1953 October (Box 7, Folder 193)
  - Intercultural Publications - Perspectives, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 194)
  - Joint Council on Educational Television, 1955-1957 (Box 7, Folder 195)
  - Katz, Milton, 1954-1956 (Box 7, Folder 196)
  - Library of Congress, 1955-1957 (Box 7, Folder 197)
  - MacKaye, Milton, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 198)
  - Mathematical Association of America, 1954-1957 (Box 7, Folder 199)
  - Miscellaneous, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 200)
  - National Academy of Science, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 201)
  - National Commission on Accrediting, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 202)
  - National Education Association, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 203)
  - National Fund for Medical Education, 1956-1958 (Box 7, Folder 204)
  - National Science Foundation, 1953-1957 (Box 7, Folder 205)
  - New York University, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 206)
  - North Carolina, University of, 1955 February-March (Box 7, Folder 207)
  - Northwestern University, 1956 March-November (Box 7, Folder 208)
  - Occidental College, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 209)
  - Princeton University, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 210)
  - Program Overview and Policy, 1954-1956 (Box 7, Folder 211)
  - Recruitment and Training Program - Interview Notes, 1956 July-October (Box 7, Folder 212)
  - Recruitment and Training Program - Policy and Planning Memos, etc., 1956 March-August (Box 7, Folder 213)
  - Rochester, University of, 1955 February-April (Box 7, Folder 214)
  - Sabbaticals, 1954-1956 (Box 7, Folder 215)
  - Secondary [Private] Schools, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 216)
  - Sigma XI, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 217)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 218)
  - Southwestern at Memphis, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 219)
  - Sponsored Research, 1954 August-September (Box 8, Folder 220)
  - Staff Projects "Icebox", 1954-1956 (Box 8, Folder 221)
  - Stanford University, 1956 March-August (Box 8, Folder 222)
  - Stephens College, 1955 January-February (Box 8, Folder 223)
  - Student Loans, 1956 January-June (Box 8, Folder 224)
  - Suchman, Edward A., 1952 September (Box 8, Folder 225)
  - Suggestions for Aid to Higher Education, 1955 January 4 (Box 8, Folder 226)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 227)
  - Tulane University, 1954-1956 (Box 8, Folder 228)
  - TV-Radio Workshop Teaching, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 229)
  - Wayne University - Research in Language Teaching, 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 230)
  - Yale University, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 231)
- Program Area V: Individual Behavior and Human Relations, 1950-1957; 1954-1956; III
  Series III consists of correspondence and inter-office memoranda. It is organized alphabetically; items within each folder are in reverse chronological order.
  - Application Summaries, 1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 232)
  - Atomic Energy, 1956 January-March (Box 9, Folder 233)
  - Berelson's European Trip, 1955 August (Box 9, Folder 234)
  - Behavioral Sciences - 5.1 Grants, 1951 September 9 (Box 9, Folder 235)
  - Behavioral Sciences - Miscellaneous, 1953-1957 (Box 9, Folder 236)
  - Budget, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 237)
  - Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Sciences, 1952-1957 (Box 9, Folder 238)
  - Chicago Law School Grant, 1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 239)
  - Desegregation Program, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 240)
  - Encyclopedia of Social Sciences, 1954-1956 (Box 9, Folder 241)
  - Fellowships, 1955 May 10 (Box 9, Folder 242)
  - Final Report, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 243)
  - Gregg, Dr. Alan, 1953-1955 (Box 9, Folder 244)
  - Juvenile Delinquency - Lebanon, 1955 February-May (Box 9, Folder 245)
  - Juvenile Delinquency - Memoranda, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 246)
  - Juvenile Delinquency - National Committee on Juvenile Delinquency, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 247)
  - Juvenile Delinquency - National Social Welfare Assembly (NSWA), 1955 January-April (Box 9, Folder 248)
  - Juvenile Delinquency - Staff Interviews on NSWA Proposal, 1955 January-May (Box 9, Folder 249)
  - Juvenile Delinquency - Senate Subcommittee to Investigate Juvenile Delinquency, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 250)